So, we're standing here in my living room
in Tokyo, Japan.  And I'm going to show
everybody just how amazing Bitcoin is by
sending a hundred euros worth of Bitcoin
as of today's value through my TV onto
the camera onto the TV in the
Netherlands and anybody with their
Bitcoin wallet ready that scans what
they're going to see on the screen in a
moment.  We'll be able to claim the 100
euros worth of Bitcoins and there's
nothing that anybody can do to stop it
or to freeze your account or block it or
control it in any way.  So, on the TV here,
we have a Bitcoin address that I've just
generated.  And I have my phone here.  I'm
going to scan the QR code for the
Bitcoin address on the TV.  Now I have it.
I'm going to send 100 euros worth of
Bitcoins to that address.  So, we'll hit send
and anybody can monitor on Blockchain.info
the balance of this address.  There
it is. 100 euros worth of Bitcoins just
arrived at this address.  So, total
received 100 euros; final balance, 100
euros, just like that.  So on this next
screen you're about to see anybody with
their Bitcoin wallet that scans the
private key that corresponds with that
address will be able to claim that
money just by scanning the code that
you're about to see on your television.
So, if you want to take a look, here it
comes, 100 euros ready for anyone to
claim.  All you have to do is scan this
one right here.  And it's 100 euros
worth of Bitcoins as of today.  By the
time you scan it, it might be worth even
more.
So, there it is for anyone ready to claim
with their Bitcoin wallet.
Okay, Holland, now you've just seen the
power of Bitcoin.  I sent 100 euros
worth of Bitcoin from here in Tokyo
directly to you guys through this camera,
through the network, through the TV right
into your home.  If I had tried to do that —
send you the money with a traditional
bank, it would have taken several days
and probably cost 30 euros.  I just did it
right now with Bitcoin instantly,
basically, for free and didn't have to
ask anybody for permission.  I didn't need
a bank.  I didn't need a government.
I didn't need anybody.  I just needed myself
and you and our smartphones to do it.
That's the power of Bitcoin. This is Back
light welcome to a world in which we can
be our own bank
we take it for granted that money
creation is controlled by governments
and banks but there's a community of
people who don't see this as a given and
to get quite worked up about it
Wall Street is fraud America is fried
the world is fraud banks are fraud
central banks are fraud live in an era
of fraud it's all based on fraud and
they get a percentage of the fraud
that's the business model to suggest
that there is any moral or ethical
aspect to anything that's going on now
is to be completely naive about the fact
that we live in an era dominated by
financial terrorists terrorists
terrorists she hotties of banking
they're here to kill you and themselves
they believe in an ideology not the
Koran but Adam Smith that they
completely miss read and interpret as
something to justify their blowing
themselves up Jerry yellows and
terrorists Marriott jaggies and
terrorists the Central Bank of Japan is
a terrorist these are the real
terrorists
those received this community is
switching to what they think is a better
monetary system a system in which banks
are no longer needed because payment
could be made directly from one person
to another the system of that one of the
two parties is always the slave and that
is the architecture of money we live in
that is the architecture of money we use
a nice civilization an architecture of
money where you have no control an
architecture of money where every
interaction is mediated by a third party
a third party that has absolute control
over that money Bitcoin is fundamentally
different because in Bitcoin you don't
owe anyone anything and no one owes you
anything it is not a system based on
that it is a system based on ownership
and no one can censor it no one can
seize it
no one can freeze it and what they will
tell you is that they're worried they're
very worried the worried that criminals
will use Bitcoin but the truth is that
they're far more terrified that all of
the rest of us will thank you
Bitcoin the cryptocurrency that was
mostly known as a convenient tool for
criminals has suddenly become an
important topic at conferences on
financial innovation all over the world
proponents speak passionately of a
digital miracle that can save the world
from financial ruin the Bitcoin story
starts off like a gospel revelation it's
November the 2nd 2008 just six weeks
after the Lehman Brothers collapse and
all over the world there are panicked
debates about how to save the banks then
on a little visited web forum for
cryptographers a document appears in
which a completely new monetary system
is proposed the visionary author calls
himself Satoshi Nakamoto
first time I heard about it I was at
lunch with a buddy in Texas and he said
man there's just crazy new money and so
he talked about it over lunch and then I
went home and I said man I want to I
want to see if I can buy some at first I
wanted to buy some
I'm emailed friend of mine I think I I
probably saw the white paper it's a web
form or something you know I just said
this is some electronic currency thing
and this was publicly available you know
this was posted
I think December you know 2008 or
something and these were the darkest
days of the financial crisis so that to
me suggests a very clever mind that saw
an opportunity the perfect opportunity
to introduce a new radical technology
and new radical approach to money in
finance at just the right moment when
people would be very open to making this
big shift its required to adopt a new
currency I'm pretty pretty sure if
Satoshi is a human being although I'd
really love to go find out they with
some advanced AI but 99.99% chance who
the human being what's exciting for me
is like a global economy right now we
say we have a global economy but I can't
take a dollar and give it to you in the
Netherlands and then you know what to do
with it right you would have to go and
change it to your native currency and
when you kind of eliminate that step and
I can just send you one form of payment
and you can send me a product in a
matter of seconds that starts to change
things from a from a global perspective
so
the first wire that I sent was a for
$25,000 and this was in early 2011 and
bitcoins were somewhere around $1 all
the way along I was buying Bitcoin and
any time I meant turn some dollars for
my other company I put it into Bitcoin
and at this point the vast majority of a
my net worth I've been keeping a Bitcoin
for a while now I'm glad you didn't get
the parking pay the car is actually like
the perfect color for Bitcoin it's like
the Bitcoin Orange so we wanted to order
some like Bitcoin decals and put like
Bitcoin logos around the car and then
drive around Tokyo to hope help
advertise a Bitcoin but still never got
around to doing that maybe someday
Roger fear is the CEO of memory dealers
com selling secondhand computer
equipment but for a couple of years now
he's been known as the Bitcoin Jesus in
2011 he bought $25,000 worth of bitcoins
which now have a market value of 6
million dollars and somebody closed my
uh I usually leave the trunk or the hood
open a little bit so that I can
reconnect the battery but I don't know
how it got closed between now and the
last time I was here so we'll have to uh
some people think of Bitcoin as sort of
an early adopter thing like okay I'm
already too late or so isn't that a
problem for Bitcoin so thinking that
that it's too late to get involved in
Bitcoin is like thinking it's too late
to get involved with the internet or too
late to get involved with using a cell
phone like it's not too late to get
involved in Bitcoin Bitcoin is going to
make your life easier in so many ways
and and the price of Bitcoin - it's not
too late for that either bitcoins like
two hundred and seventy dollars a
Bitcoin right now if Bitcoin becomes
really popular all over the world
bitcoins are going to have to be worth
at least tens of thousands of dollars a
Bitcoin if not hundreds of thousands of
dollars per Pig per Bitcoin so thinking
it's too late to get involved with with
Bitcoin is like thinking it's too late
to get involved with with using the
Internet of course not like it's
ubiquitous in our lives and bitcoins
going to become ubiquitous in our lives
as well
perfect money should be have a limited
supply that's one of the most important
things needs have a limited supply it
needs to be easily recognizable it needs
to be durable it needs to be
transportable Bitcoin has all those
things better than any other form of
money the world has ever seen and that's
why when I noticed Bitcoin for the first
time I realized that it's so incredibly
useful as money that people are going to
start using it more and more
Roger lives and works in Tokyo
he's outsourcing all the work for his
own company so he can spend all his time
promoting Bitcoin so it's a pretty
exciting time for Bitcoin right now with
all the stuff going on in in Greek I
mean bitcoins up about ten dollars since
yesterday just since all the news on the
Greek referendum vote and just every day
bitcoins so exciting so on you can see
you know lots of trading and everything
just in the last 24 hours there I paid
to put up a billboard in the heart of
Silicon Valley right next to one of the
busiest expressways that just said we
accept Bitcoin memory dealers calm and
then listed some of the parts that we
sell then after that I started paying
for national radio ads in the United
States - Ron more than a hundred radio
stations across the United States and
paid for that for a couple of years okay
wave a popular consumer website in Japan
will accept bitcoins from now on at a
press conference
Roger fear helps them spread the word
well today one Bitcoin is Salman goes on
in Nairobi Canseco challenging in
atrocity nam kyuman in token insane man
in naka de valera is it a Bitcoin
Warneke Nina Rajasthan car seats may we
stated a key muscle there was a sad day
he out of the coal cause it's me
imani new I call you Quattro an Aikido
no Nathalie Sanwa what assured in Hangul
mind occur a Nihonjin naka Rod Carew a
to touch the copper-colored smashed it
could hit economist Inka animal Sukhoi
hello can anyone say toma de monaco a
career on disc a domo an Opie Tokui
Valdes knee and OTC ryomou ha karana
Qatari toka Ito sugoku Tommy sigatoka
Qatari a she's a super open an associate
REI toes who could open any other a to G
only also sunny quit their ego saga if I
arrow to go to destiny so you my Marino
at Cohn oh my no Connie you are how you
cut or chop to re master like at all
Imam are anyone engine erection no koto
EEMA size Chikara imam are a bit corner
Ichiban call you go to mathura crowd
it's a kite Shinhwa each one e economy
learning a bit coins I forgot mantra in
Makarova could've asked you oh good
hideout
hi IRA so go build an eye on there so
yeah prinster - Tamar - show demo kya
Sinan boon Bitcoin wantonness a cartoon
in Kannada yeah c'mon in Nara no
Colossians Artemis George are you giving
bit please away
I'm giving you every Pope every single
person here 1000 yen worth of bitcoins
which is like $8 in something cents
that's a refreshment my dog okay
I've given away thousands of whole
bitcoins to just various people on
Facebook that would post their Bitcoin
address and this is back when bitcoins
were a couple of dollars each so I'm
sure those people are pretty happy at
this point how could this digital coin
invented by this Satoshi Nakamoto become
hundreds of times more valuable than the
dollar and why do enthusiasts like Roger
fear want the world to switch to
bitcoins to understand this we need to
look at how new bitcoins are created a
complex process called mining
promotional videos make it look as if
everyone can just mine bitcoins millions
of people all over the world earn real
crypto money daily it's quite simple
just download the special software
connect to the web and wait for your
profits to roll in for mining you don't
need any special knowledge you can mine
at home at work or to cafe anywhere
there's access to the Internet in fact
lots of people have already received a
good income from mining it's interesting
just to get us to get you out of the bed
in the morning no it doesn't I get it
it doesn't get you out of the bed in the
morning no it doesn't I get it marshal
Leung was one of the world's first
Bitcoin miners now he's the CEO of final
hash a company that professionally mines
bitcoins okay well that's fine we can we
can talk about it more in Chicago that's
fine so back in the early days you know
I get phone calls from my buddies oh hey
man I lost 10,000 bitcoins because my
computer blew up right back then one
Bitcoin was less than a penny right so
nobody cared they lost $10 I don't care
right now 10,000 bitcoins that's you
know five million dollars that's a big
deal right so now it's interesting to
see how the industry has changed there
wasn't YouTube videos and all these nice
things to show you how to mine so it
took me about three weeks to hook up
computer up to figure out how to do this
mining and you know back in the good
days that you could take a laptop like
this and
you could mine maybe a hundred or two
hundred coins in a day when summer time
in Houston came my wife was like this AC
has been on for 24 hours it's really hot
what were you doing up there I said oh
you know I'm just running some computers
and she walks up there and you know you
see 50 graphics cards all running at the
same time and it's very hot she's like
okay you got a you got to get out of
here you got to figure something else
out cuz it is too hot hey what's up nerd
you have some fans cheering here aka
barnacle YZ I'm here with Marshall long
from hath final hash now we're out here
and I would say what's going to be the
largest Bitcoin mine in North America
and it's realistically an actual mining
operation like you can pretty much
attribute everything that's going on
here to like a real gold mining
operation it's like you have heavy
equipment you have cost you fuel cost
yeah and you have recovery everything
that you then go and sell and turn into
real money that's right
okay how many of these machines are in
here you got a scores s5 everyday
actually this is mostly a scores
literally the loudest place ever it's
like he in a wing
cooling in here is so efficient and if
you put your hand back here behind the
units where they're drawing here it's
freezing cold it is nice ice cold air
coming in here you put your hand in the
front down the center
is burning burning hi profitable
a Bitcoin as the reward for solving
complex mathematical puzzles and Bitcoin
miners let their computers work day and
night to complete these tasks all the
Bitcoin users in the world are connected
and together they constitute a network
that processes and checks all Bitcoin
transactions in a public ledger called
the blockchain and Satoshi Nakamoto
designed it in such a way that users can
create a free and anonymous Bitcoin
account number a so called wallet
satoshis invention eliminates the need
for a central bank because all the users
together are the bank but early Bitcoin
users had no idea how big Bitcoin and
the blockchain would become I think
sometime in spring of 2010 I could be
wrong on the exact dates but basically
someone put out a request saying hey I'd
like to buy something with Bitcoin will
anyone buy me a pizza and I believe
someone here in England bought the the
person in Florida a pizza for ten
thousand or something bitcoins and maybe
worth you know a very large sum of money
today and and that was the first Bitcoin
commercial transaction garrick Heilmann
an economist at the London School of
Economics was one of the first scholars
to study Bitcoin and the blockchain as a
serious monetary system as a scholar at
you should label it was something
totally new to you it looked very
different to me I mean as soon as I
heard the word decentralized and the
fact there was a network powering this
currency rather than a central issuer
that immediately captured my interest is
something quite different based on what
little I knew about alternative
currencies at that time what it meant
for people who are libertarians in
particular is that the government
couldn't come in and shut down a server
and in Bitcoin it would have to shut
down the entire internet or turn off the
electricity grid - to stop Bitcoin and
so that was really attractive - to
people who are worried about these types
of things many of the early Bitcoin
enthusiasts were libertarians who saw
Bitcoin
as the ultimate remedy for state
intervention this was also what
attracted Roger Vere to Bitcoin in his
early 20s he was a candidate for the
Libertarian Party in California but
during his campaign he was sentenced to
ten months in prison for trafficking
illegal fireworks according to him this
was a political case brought by people
who opposed his ideas I have a two
Bitcoin related Gea's I have the Bitcoin
org
and I have the blockchain that info
Bitcoin blockchain logo anything was a
political case there's no doubt in my
mind whatsoever and in fact even at one
of the pre-trial conference things with
the ATF agents my attorney in the US
attorney might renew saying hey these
are store-bought firecrackers we sold on
eBay we can pay a fine and do some
community service and you down with this
there's no reason to destroy my life
over it and send me to prison to make me
a felon and the US Attorney at that
point was kind of nodding his head like
that sounds reasonable the ATF agent
literally pounded his hand on the table
and shed it but you didn't hear the
things that he said which I think summed
up very clearly they weren't mad about
anything that I had done they're not
about the things that I had said because
the ideas that I'm trying to spread are
subversive to the state I did ten months
in federal prison and I was scared of
the US government the moment I was
allowed to leave the u.s. I left and I
haven't lived there ever since and they
have what's called an exit act so at the
time you announced your United States
citizen they tax you on your entire net
worth that capital gains tax rates and
you have to pay them that money
otherwise they'll probably either send
you to jail or at the very least not
ever let you back in the country ever
again if you think about it it's not all
that different than you slaves from the
past having to buy their freedom from
the plantation owners money creation by
the state is sort of connected to state
aggression for you right in my line of
thinking is if you are I create
counterfeit euros or print euros or
dollars or yen we would go to jail for
counterfeiting because it's destructive
to the economy by counterfeiting dollars
it's stealing everybody else in the
economy that has money when governments
do the exact same thing it has the exact
same negative effects the only
difference is they call it fancy names
like quantitative easing or economic
stimulus but it is destructive for the
exact same reasons
my hobby growing up and in high school
and since has been studying economics
and the more you study economics the
more you realize that all these
government interventions in the economy
prevent the world from becoming as
wealthy and prosperous as it otherwise
would become and suddenly now we have
this tool that separates money from
state like everybody today thinks that
separating church and state of course
they should be separated but a couple
hundred years ago it was you know heresy
just hit that church the state should be
separated and today it sounds maybe a
little bit crazy to say that money and
state should be separate but I think in
another decade or two people are going
to think Oh what the heck were we
thinking letting governments be in
charge of money that cost so many
problems in so many misallocation of
resources around the world of course
bitcoin is is better okay
these feathers pick
why is the government's and banks
monopoly on money creation seen as
undesirable in his white paper Satoshi
Nakamoto didn't express his opinion on
this but it does seem that he wanted
bitcoins to appreciate rather than
depreciate unlike money he programmed
Bitcoin in such a way that there's a
maximum of 21 million bitcoins to be
mined bitcoins weren't meant to resemble
money but gold in November 2013 this
dream became reality when one bitcoin
was worth an ounce of gold the Bitcoin
code itself has never been hacked but in
2014 the customer data of Mount GOx an
online exchange office was stolen by
hackers causing the Bitcoin exchange
rate to plummet
at the Financial Times in London
journalist Isabella Kaminski has been
critically following the Bitcoin
exchange rate and community since the
very beginning I've always been a geek
about finance and I've always been a
geek about how the system works so like
the really boring nuts and bolts the
plumbing of the system and I think in
2008 it was the first time we all really
fought actually not only is the system
as it as we know it possibly crumbling
there might be opportunities for new
systems to come up as a result of it
exactly why I guess I start writing
about it again around here 2012 and then
we had the first little rally and then
this is also clasp this is very
reminiscent to the classic bubble I know
each other so you see this is the this
is the famous bubble chart which has
take off first Elif bear traps as the
first little micro you know
mini dump and you go to the new total
bubble then it crashes and is a bit of
like a return people think maybe it's
going to come back and then it crashes
again and then it it gets back to a more
realistic trajectory and you'll see that
that really is very reminiscent to what
we've seen here what everyone is really
wondering is will we see a consolidation
of this price or will it recover
somewhat or will it go completely to
zero and we're really what do you think
I think what's best for Bitcoin is
actually if it just stays stable so
everybody agrees volatility is currently
the the biggest enemy of Bitcoin so
she's dreamed what would that be the
paper doesn't really say what his big
dream was he just wanted an efficient
mechanism that was cheap but in terms of
what I think people have projected his
vision as being is this world where we
are we are are all our own
Banke we don't have to depend on any
intermediary and thanks are gone in the
current economy because of the way our
system is structured if I decide to hold
my dollars I'm usually holding them in
an institution that is using them as a
means of capital raising and they will
be lending them out so my money even
though I'm saving that saving is going
into an investment somewhere else being
done by a bank etc and it's helping to
grow the economy
so my saving doesn't disadvantage the
economy but in Bitcoin there isn't that
that opportunity so hoard of Bitcoin as
a hoarded it Bitcoin it's totally idle
it has no interest it has no yield it is
simply sitting there doing nothing and
yet the person who holds on to it thinks
they have a right to future income flow
as if they have been invested in when
the line was flat people like massively
boring or mined bitcoins and they are
now like multi-millionaire billionaires
they're the new 1% they're the 1% of the
Bitcoin economy which again goes against
the whole democratization side of the
argument because really you're not
democratizing the economy you're just
transferring the power from the existing
elite to a new elite the fact that a few
early Bitcoin miners and investors are
now multimillionaires is reminiscent of
the current banking system in which
bankers are accused of personal
enrichment
so I got this degree in international
development and as I was with my dog on
his Hill and I was like yeah what could
I do go try and work and so me I say
East Africa I could go and explore
economies there and see what's happening
like at rallies things and I was like
why don't I just try and break into the
financial sector in London that would
actually be really really fascinating
that'd be really amazing and then once I
had that thought I couldn't I mean I
just became obsessed with this idea
bread scott is the author of the book
hacking the future of money about
reforming the financial sector to
immerse himself in the system he
criticized he worked for two years as a
broker in the city of London we're now
in the city we just passed the border
tracking huh his dragons mark the
boundaries of the City of London it's
the financial district
cut off of my hair I bought my first
suit interestingly enough I had two
interviews with Lehman Brothers
literally weeks before they went bust
and I remember being up and the 35th
floor or something and the guy was like
I know everything's fine everything's
fine here
yeah don't believe the stories heshes
you've seen the press about us and then
they went and if you created an entire
society it was reliant in Bitcoin yeah
you'd have massive problems with
inequality but it's it's very important
in that if it's forms a kind of counter
power to the existing bank payment
system so while I can critique Bitcoin
as much as you want you know I'm always
aware that's you know the glistening
Bank system is highly flawed and I
lacked the fact that this exists as an
alternative what's happening right now
and a lot of the banking scene is moved
towards it's called a cashless society
but if you think what that actually
means it means every single payment that
you undertake has to go via a commercial
bank now that means every single
transaction you you ever do will be
monitored and recorded in a database
somewhere it means you'll always be
giving fees to various you know credit
card companies and so on so there's
there's potential achievements of
surveillance there's all sorts of
problems that come with a cashless
society in that world something like
Bitcoin which is an electronic version
of cash or electronic full of I guess an
electronic equivalent to cash becomes
quite important
so st. Paul's Cathedral
which is a
we're the Occupy movement set up camp
London without their for long term they
tried to occupy the London Stock
Exchange but weren't able to get in the
show st. Paul's instead you think of
Bitcoin and the whole movement being as
a sort of better form of Occupy it's a
different full of occupy you know it's a
maybe it's a follow-on from the Occupy
movement in some ways Bitcoin as a form
of protest against the current banking
system is propagated in the Netherlands
by three Bitcoin enthusiasts who have
created an app called bit Casa and who
are now trying to convince all retailers
in arnhem to accept bitcoins a zucchini
mensis break over bitcoin magnatag's
Anniston see some strength of phone over
control and not be humble and apart my
judgment they talk emanates from woods
hydric systemic like a mocha a second at
this talk bainer
bananita slovenly hundred events will
endure chimeric fact that started via
sound of alternate for night only
daughter implying club people infuse the
olive health market and not vanity
liners individual markers buddy -
saucers override that by debunk a mood
Elena
totally bonkers letter like added neat
marker this yeah that's being super safe
I was in year the plot home phone Arnhem
the dissipated syndrome from the start
we have here at motor Cartier and yeah
you see that the Bitcoin except on the
shitter for spry admirers manam and
syndrome have an enormous wrote over
white bitcoin except don't graze on the
arrows on a vehicle looked at every nano
done from a key item at hood yeah
you can open after friday's we stayed in
cannot vein museum before wheels and
bowler house that office kill in the
tourists legs I've been going to rest
the special items I'd gone that yeah
here each have opposite from a home
network and weekend and I looked at
canal and lay my bitcoins come cannot
save I was the fellow lonely storm at
the battalion lonely enough over me
general inclement agrees he a Dogma to
Matt Bitcoin yeah I got my ugly I love
all dead all dead
yeah aglet evil meows the single map
layer that is off a thermo VG e tennis
circuit of GDP not my heart of the pin
pushes meridian elope - Matt foam and
ashes the bunker the name dynamic wound
difficult for Ollis single moody
penultimate Mooji of coke in with bundle
scope and on distorting with all the
da-da-da-dum of ameica opt out that cos
want to feel go and we also the name of
characters bitcoins yeah I got fear
baitcaster same caterpillars out loud
yeah and vanish out who the fuck is
leading to only bitcoins to how and
silicone it on creative energy cultural
as bitcoins as it act that via click
home slot you started act at UK like
acting the Gothic leg for young skin or
cardigan and snowball Jolla the study me
award and ibn Affan or knockout Loki and
um Cameroon father Dhaka common father
that incidentally I don't yeah I just
feel really big concerns I'll be all
multiply going to be part of magma sale
and most for skillful Julie met dr. Phil
Mia interview cars we meet Expo chaps
super which was New York the Nets
out of a Salt Lake necessity of it's all
fake beside the ease of use the Arnim
students have also noticed a less
pleasant quality to bitcoins
the fluctuating exchange rate compared
to other currencies which could make a
beer a couple of cents cheaper or more
expensive between ordering and serving
so Bitcoin in my mind effing ition is
not money the key to something being
money in my opinion is that it's a
widely used unit of account meaning that
goods and services are priced in it so
when you go to the coffee shop you see
something priced in Bitcoin that's not
true
there are coffee shops where there are
prices in Bitcoin but that price is
changing constantly based on the
currency it's linked to so the pound for
example here in England lost 20% of its
value recently but the price of coffee
didn't change it was still 99 p
that's what it means to be a unit of
account and bitcoin is not that the
price adjusts based on its exchange rate
continuously do you see the Bitcoin as a
form of money or as a digital gold so I
see gold as money and I see Bitcoin as
having all the same properties of gold
with one property that actually couple
properties are even better so gold is
kind of hard to divide Bitcoin divides
down to eight decimal points instantly
super easily
Gold is really really difficult to
transport if I want to transport gold
from here to Moscow it'll cost a bunch
of money to do that and it's dangerous
you have to have armed guards and who
knows what with Bitcoin I can simba coin
from here to Moscow or to the Holland
instantly just like that basically for
free I don't have to pay for a bunch of
armed guards it just happens almost like
magic if you ever ask somebody why they
think Gold's valuable I can already tell
you though it feels like weird stories
around ads like a precious metal isn't
it it it's pretty while we think it has
all its intrinsic value this intrinsic
value of gold has been largely
constructed in people's here it's often
by a shield like association with power
association with religious figures and
Bitcoin and has potential for similar
types of construction you could create
this the sense of this almost like a
commodity like token that has no
immediate sort of value to it but can be
imbued with value
as more people start to mind they become
harder and harder to find so it's kind
of been at I correlated to like an arms
race right the guy with the biggest gun
wins at this point so this is the newest
place we've started working on here this
is a place in the mountains in China
it's cool and it doesn't rain that much
so we can cool it very efficiently how
much do you pay for that electricity on
a daily basis
um I'll lend all of my minds together
we're probably paying about $100,000
maybe a little bit more a day yeah I'm
paying 100,000 is per month I'm sorry
okay but Bitcoin in general all myself
and all my colleagues combined it's
about a million dollars a day in power
in power consumption and you guys
generate what worth of coins we're
generating of course it depends on the
price right but price right so we'll
just say for 250 now we'll just put the
price at $250 for easy numbers you're
finding roughly around 25 bitcoins every
10 minutes so you just take that and
times it by an hour so you're finding
around 150 bitcoins an hour take that
times 24 and you do that times 250 do
some packet of so we're making about 900
thousand dollars per day so a lot of
people ask how is that possible and that
the reality is a lot of the Chinese guys
they are mining at a negative profit one
of my friends in Beijing I met him last
month I met him up again and I asked him
last time I checked man your power was
pretty expensive why are you still
mining and his only words were I can't
stop so what do you mean you can't stop
you're losing money it's like well I
can't I have all these you know pieces
of equipment and I just can't stop it's
gold fever right that's right and it's
interesting because a lot of the a lot
of my colleagues don't see it as a
business
subconsciously right
get addicted to it and kind of get crazy
about it
how's your neck and although every woman
they got talent um doing the diva just
one medallion that you Haji far seen a
or Saint hello mrs. 100-yard huh
sambhar bubby did yeah a guy Oh sunshine
hydro the gong-gong have a shortage
hearts out raikou no sent over to Roger
Langille guru Tai Kwan a front on the
Heil IP oh yeah let's wait awhile
I'm the cerulean guys you can call that
Joshua I'm gonna sue seed of Eve our
young boy I shall walk agenda see Paris
and put out a deluge yet we look hungry
GC a collage of your signature han
dong-su palace oh gee
so what was supposed to be a very
democratic system has ended up
concentrating it exactly the same way
that we have seen the bank's concentrate
their business so now you have most of
the miners are based in China or most of
the miners are huge server farms that
you know the average person can't be a
miner anymore in Bitcoin it's far the
the the barriers to entry are now really
really quite expensive that you have to
invest in at least you know you
thousands of dollars of equipment if you
want to be a miner and a lot of people
who got into the first year Bitcoin
actually had mental breakdowns it was so
beautiful it was like you're seeing you
know some of the most remarkable art
ever for the first time one of the
qualities that I don't like about the
community is that it's extremely
absolutist it's very politically led and
it assumes that it's political ideology
is the correct one and it kind of
Frost's its pursue ideology on everybody
else
so say you know I don't want political
ideology when I'm paying for my coffee I
just want a payment network that works
and that allows me to benefit from
smooth transaction
lots of paper money
so this is a receipt and this is my
public address and private key you got
it covered for us so we cannot film it
that's right
over the past two years new members are
increasingly joining the Bitcoin
community not for ideological reasons
but for practical ones in Kiev there are
some protests happening so people start
using social media to share their QR
code within a matter of days they
automatically had fifteen thousand
dollars in their wallets from
sympathizers to the protest that money
was transferred from around the world
say incredibly powerful example because
today I spent seven years in Nicaragua
and today I still cannot use PayPal to
transfer money to my friends in
Nicaragua whether or not Bitcoin will be
worth millions isn't the main question
for many computer scientists investors
and hackers to them Satoshi nakamoto's
real invention is the blockchain
technology a global open ledger which
can be used to share much more than just
money
you may think that bitcoin is just
another way to pay for a cup of coffee
but it's not Bitcoin is just the
denomination used to pay the toll to put
stuff on this school baletta
now if you think about it time stamp
recordings of deaths births property
transactions votes this is the entire
fabric of our civilization which makes
the blockchain one of the most profound
human innovations of our time because
having a massive global ledger as a
public utility can completely reorganize
the way that we run our societies
fundamentally blockchain is a database
sort of mechanism and it's a standard
it's a protocol and one of the problems
we have in an increasingly globalized
system is that everyone is operating
their systems on their own local
standards and getting people to do
everything in a uniform way that
benefits all of us like you know
bringing
in the metric system that is really
really hard blockchain offers an
opportunity to start this new exciting
technological you know industry from a
standard that is globalized and
potentially uniform so I see the
potential that way the decentralized
blockchain makes it possible to share
data publicly without a single party
controlling the system in the blockchain
all participants in the network are
equal maybe inventor Satoshi Nakamoto so
Bitcoin is just the first experiment
with this form of digital democracy I
think blockchain technologies really
authentically fascinating like I think
it's anybody who ignores it and in rats
Adolphe is probably making a mistake I
think it's definitely not going to get
it it's not going to get smaller but to
this day the true identity of the
architect behind this revolutionary
technology remains a mystery you know we
can't ask the toshi questions which is
really frustrating right but it's also
again part of I think the magic of
Bitcoin is that you know we can all kind
of imagine this technology you know for
you know as we see it rather than just
as Satoshi did so it could be used in
this way even if Satoshi didn't intend
it to intend it to be this widely
worldwide distributed thing I think I
think Satoshi probably did but you know
it still could be that and we can we can
make it that Satoshi around here
somewhere in Tokyo
yeah I think I see him right there oh
that's a question I get a lot actually
um a lot of people have asked me who
Satoshi is since I got in so early um I
think I've got a pretty good idea but I
like to keep that one close to my chest
so why um because I'm not a hundred
percent certain and the reality is it
doesn't really matter right it doesn't
matter who Satoshi is because now it's
kind of grown beyond like a pet project
right but I mean Satoshi
how much how many coins I think these
got about 500,000 locked up with his
blockchain technology inventor Satoshi
Nakamoto has completely relinquished his
control of Bitcoin but he does own one
twentieth of all bitcoins himself so if
one day Bitcoin does become widely
accepted as a currency he will be one of
the richest people on earth people might
find that scary a new currency or system
based on an inventor who owns already
well one twentieth of all the currency
invented yeah isn't that a problem
Satoshi invented one of the most
important inventions in the entire
history of humankind that's going to
improve the lives of everybody on the
planet for the better if he had half of
all the bitcoins he would still deserve
it who do you think Satoshi is I think
it's probably a band of people who
decided that a nom de plume was the best
way to go precisely because if it did
take off there would be too many
consequences for a individual one person
or even a group of people and from my
perspective you never make a move of
this sort without a myth you need a sort
of foundation myth every good sort of
system of power has a foundation myth
and it's always best if there if the
leader is either anonymous or aloof or
in some way distant from the public
because you have to create a sort of
mythology around him and because Satoshi
nobody knows he is
some University if we knew who he was it
would almost it would almost ruin the
whole thing for everybody I think
why don't you disappear anything ah he
undermined the ability of every single
government on the entire planet to
control the money supply and that's how
every single government in the world is
controlling their citizens and their
economies today and he just basically
you know knocked their feet right out
from under them with the invention of
Bitcoin and I'm sure that's going to
make a lot of people who want to control
other people by force
I'm really really upset so yeah I think
it's really really smart for him to have
a disappeared and for me it probably
would have been smarter for me to keep
quiet - but bitcoins too exciting for me
to just stay quiet about
I think a lot of people are under
estimating the way in which Bitcoin and
the blockchain are going to change the
power structures in society in general
I'm and I grew up in the US and uh
I see all these people like yeah nuke
everybody in the Middle East and kill
them all and then they have the former
Secretary of State Madeleine Albright on
60 minutes one of the most popular news
shows in the US and they asked her they
said like there's reports that more than
half a million Iraqi children have died
as a direct result of US sanctions and
she looks back at her with a straight
face and she goes it was a really tough
decision but I think that it was worth
it
worth murdering half a million kids
because of what the government did and I
apologized for crying but it just
disgusts me from my core when I see
government people murdering people
around the world it's not just
theoretical these were real people with
real lives
and it's real people and bitcoin has the
power to undermine everything they're
doing to people around the world and I'm
sorry for shouting but it just disgusts
me what these people in government - and
they do it through central banking and
through the control of the money supply
and Bitcoin takes that away from them
you